Guide to the Margaret Hodges Papers, 1911-2006 SC.1990.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Children's Books, 1960-2006; VI.
  - Don Quixote and Sancho Panza, 1986-1993; 33.
    - Typescript 5, Final With Editor Notes and Letter (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Typescript 6, Introducing the Reader to Two Travelers (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Reviews (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - The Golden Deer, 1989-1992; 34.
    - Research (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence From Charles Scribner's Sons, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence to Charles Scribner's Sons, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Typescript 2, Final (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Reviews (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - The Hero of Bremen, 1988-1996; 35.
    Published in 1993 by Holiday House.
    - Research, Including Slides (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Research, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, Including Photograph, 1989-1996 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to and From Little, Brown and Co., 1989 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Typescript 3, Final With Editor and Publisher Notes (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Illustrator Information on Charles Mikolayck, Including Obituary, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Book Reviews, 1993-1996 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Awards and Honors, Parent's Choice, Texas Bluebonnet, Kentucky Bluegrass, 1993-1996 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Of Swords and Sorcerers: The Adventures of King Arthur and His Knights, 1991-1993; 36.
    Publish in 1993 by Scribner.
    - Research, Including Photographs (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence From Charles Scribner's Sons, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence to Charles Scribner's Sons, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Typescript 3, Final (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Flap Copy Proof (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Illustrations, Copies (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Book Reviews (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - St. Patrick and the Peddler, 1991-1997; 37.
    Published in 1993 by Orchard Books.
    - Research (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence From Orchard Books, 1992-1997 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence to Orchard Books, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Typescript 4 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Typescript 5 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence to Paul Brett Johnson, Illustrator, 1993-1994 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Reviews, 1993-1994 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Hidden in the Sand, 1989-1995; 38.
    Published in 1994 by Scribner's.
    - Research (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence to Place Manuscript, 1989-1992 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence From Charles Scribner's Sons, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence to Charles Scribner's Sons, 1992-1994 (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence From Atheneum, 1994-1995 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Typescript 4 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Flap Copy (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Reviews, 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Gulliver in Lilliput, 1991-1995; 39.
    Published in 1995 by Holiday House.
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1991-1995 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1991-1995 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Typescript 1, Gulliver's Pockets (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Typescript With Editor and Publisher Notes (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Flap Copy, Draft and Revised Copy (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Dedication Copy Proof, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Reviews, 1995-1996 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Comus, 1988-1996; 40.
    Published in 1996 by Holiday House.
    - Research, General (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Research, Ludlaw (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1989-1996 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1988-1996 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Early Typescript (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Typescript 2, The Lady Enters (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Typescript 3, Final (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence From Trina Schart Hyman, Illustrator, 1989-1995 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence to Trina Schart Hyman, Illustrator, 1989-1991 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Reviews, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Molly Limbo, 1992-1996; 41.
    Published in 1996 by Atheneum Books for Young Readers.
    - Research (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence to Place Manuscript, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence From Publishers, 1993-1996 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence to Publisher, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Typescript (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Text Proof (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof 1 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof 2 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Illustrations Sample (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Reviews (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Silent Night: The Song and Its Story, 1956-1997; 42.
    Published in 1997 by Eerdman's Books for Young Readers.
    - Research, Including Photographs (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Research, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to Place Manuscript, 1994-1996 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence From Eerdman's, 1996-1997 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence to Eerdman's, 1995-1997 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Let's Tell a Story, Edited Typescript, 12/10/1956 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Galleys and Proofs, Text Proofs (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Reviews, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Promotional Materials, Including Photographs (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - The True Tale of Johnny Appleseed, 1993-1999; 43.
    Published in 1997 by Holiday House.
    - Research (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence to Place Manuscript, 1993-1998 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1993-1997 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1993-1996 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Typescript 3, Miscellaneous Pages (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Artwork by Illustrator, Signed (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Reviews, 1997-1999 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Book Awards, Parenting Magazine and Parent's Choice, 1998-1999 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Up the Chimney, 1997-1998; 44.
    Published in 1998 by Holiday House.
    - Research (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1997-1998 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Typescript 2, Final (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Proof, Title Page Setting Copy (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Jacket Copy Proof (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - Illustrator's Sample, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Reviews (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Joan of Arc: The Lily Maid, 1992-2000; 45.
    Published in 1999 by Holiday House.
    - Correspondence to Place Manuscript, 1992-1993 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1994-1998 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1994-1997 (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - Outline and Typescripts (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - Typescript, Final (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Title Page, Setting Copy (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence With Trina Schart Hyman, Original Illustrator (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - Reviews, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - Awards, Parent's Choice, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - Moses, 1999; 46. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Published in 1999 by Harcourt Brace.
    - Folded and Gathered Proof, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The Boy Who Drew Cats, 2002; 47.
    Published in 2002 by Holiday House.
    - Typescript (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence From Aki Sogabe, Illustrator, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Reviews and Articles, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - The Legend of St. Christopher: From The Golden Legend, 1984-2004; 48.
    Published in 2002 by Eerdmans Books for Young Readers.
    - Correspondence From Publisher, 1990-2002 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to Publisher, 1992-2001 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Corrected Typescripts, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Text Proof (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Galley Proof, Corrected (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Book Reviews and Awards, 2002-2004 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Publication in The Living Church Magazine, 1984-1989 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Merlin and the Making of the King, 2002-2004; 49.
    Published in 2004 by Holiday House.
    - Research (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 2003-2005 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence From Trina Schart Hyman, Illustrator, Including Photographs, 2002-2004 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Typescripts (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Galley Proof, With Author Notes (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Galley Proof, With Illustrations (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Photocopy (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Reviews (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Dick Whittington and His Cat, 1999-2006; 50.
    Published in 2006 by Holiday House.
    - Research (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2005 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Typescripts (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Galley Proof (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Books Edited, 1960-1997; 51.
    - Elva S. Smith's The History of Children's Literature, 1974-1997
      Published by the American Library Association, 1980. Edited by Margaret Hodges and Susan Steinfirst.
      - Correspondence With Publisher, 1974-1979 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence With Susan Steinfirst and Husband, Gene Story, Including Obituary, 1977-1997 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence With George Smith, 1979-1982 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Other Correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Stories to Tell Children, Correspondence and Reviews, 1960-1975 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      1960
  - Unpublished, 1978-1997; 52.
    - The Road Turned Upside Down, 1978-1989
      Also called "The Road to Canterbury" and "Easy Money."
      - Research (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1978-1989 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Notes and Outline (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Manuscripts, The Road to Canterbury (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Typescripts, The Road to Canterbury (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Monsters and Other Strangers
      - Research and Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Manuscripts (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Typescripts (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - The Champion, Typescript and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Elsie Piddock Skips in Her Sleep, Typescript (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - One Eye, 1992
      - Manuscript and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Never Give Up, 1992-1993
      - Correspondence and Research, 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Manuscripts and Typescripts, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Christmas Everyday, 1991-1992
      - Typescripts and Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - St. Nicholas Comes to Manhattan and Mr. Moore and Me, 1990-1991
      - Research, Including Slides (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Manuscript (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - The Tempest
      - Research and Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Manuscript and Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Paul Revere's Ride, Research and Typescript, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Pecos Bill, Typescripts and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - The Lad Who Went to the North Wind, Typescripts and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - A Cat's Tale, Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - The Gift of Hiathawa, 1991-1997
      Also called "The Harvest of Hiawatha"
      - Research (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - Typescript, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Washington
      - Research (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - Typescripts (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Guide to Illustrators, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Anthology of Children's Literature, Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 36, Folder 25)
- Other Writing, 1981-2002; VII.
  Writings by Hodges that do not fit easily into any other category. Included are short stories adapted from other sources, a draft of what appears to be her only attempt at an adult fiction story, poetry, personal essays, a local newsletter that she contributed to, classwork for her graduate classes, and research and ideas for works she never wrote.
  - Adapted Short Stories, 1.
    - The Army of the Dead, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Androclese and the Lion, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Cinderella, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - The Gingerbread Boy, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - The Little Orphan Annie, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Little Toe Bone, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Marley's Ghost, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Old Man Gulley's Hat, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - The Remember Service, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Fiction, Sister Angela, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Poetry, 2.
    - Original Works by Hodges (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Works Used by Hodges (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Personal Essays, 3.
    - Are You a Successful Hostess?, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Cinderella Ball, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Drop That Load, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Glorious Fourth, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Wassail!, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - What are Fairytales?, Manuscript (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Wild Blue Yonde, Typescript (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Newsletter, The Longview, 2000-2002 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Continuing Education and Class Work, 1981-1983; 4.
    - Milton Seminar, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Religion 214, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - English Literature 205: Middle English Survey, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - English Literature 261: Epic Backgrounds, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - English Literature 207 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Research, Mandalay by Kipling (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Reference Materials (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Ideas in Progress (Box 37, Folder 28)
- Media, 1947-1988; VIII.
  Various media, including video (U-matic, VHS, DVD), grooved discs, audio cassettes, and 35mm slides that document Hodge's storytelling career, research, and teaching.
  - Let's Tell A Story Grooved Discs, 1947- 1954; undated; 1.
    Scope and Contents
    Recordings of Let's Tell a Story, a regionally broadcast show on Pittsburgh's WCAE radio station. The grooved discs are housed in 20 boxes that contain 15 aluminum cored discs each for a total of 300 discs arranged according to broadcast date. Each labelled double-sided disc contains one to three programs with one to three stories per program drawn from folk and fairy tales.
  - Tell Me A Story Video Recordings, circa 1960-1976; 2.
    Materials pertaining to Tell Me A Story, a nationally broadcast television program on Pittsburgh's WQED-TV that aired from the mid-1960's to 1976. Items are housed in nine boxes that include the original U-matic recordings. The collection also contains reformatted versions on VHS, DVD and Digital files. Each item contains two to four episodes of the program. Please contact Ask an Archivist to request access to view digitized episodes. Please include details of the specific episode/s that are of interest.
    - Episodes: The Emperor's New Clothes and The Wave
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 38, Tape 1)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 38, Video 1)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 30 minutes (Box 38, Disc 1)
    - Episodes: The Twelve Dancing Princesses; The Cat and the Parrott; The Ugly Duckling; The Tiger, The Brahman, and The Jackal
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 38, Tape 2)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 38, Video 2)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 38, Disc 2)
    - Episodes: Jack and the Beanstalk; Gone is Gone; The Bremen Town Musicians; Snow White
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 38, Tape 3)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 38, Video 3)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 38, Disc 3)
    - Episodes: The Fisherman and The Genie; Pinocchio; The Blind Men and The Elephant; My Mother is the Most Beautiful Woman in the World
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 39, Tape 1)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 39, Video 1)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 39, Disk 1)
    - Episodes: Here After This; Little Snow Girl; Sorcerer; The Elephant's Child
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 39, Tape 2)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 39, Video 2)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 39, Disc 2)
    - Episodes: Puss in Boots; Hansel and Gretel; The Cock, The Mouse, and The Little Red Hen; Cinderella
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 39, Tape 3)
        Four episodes: Puss in Boots; Hansel and Gretel; The Cock, The Mouse, and The Little Red Hen; Cinderella
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 39, Video 3)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 39, Disc 3)
    - Episodes: The Three Sillies; Stone Soup; Lazy Jack; The Elves and The Shoemaker
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 40, Tape 1)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 40, Video 1)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 40, Disc 1)
    - Episodes: The Fire Bringer; Dick Whittington and His Cat; Andy and The Lion; Noah's Ark
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 40, Tape 2)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 40, Video 2)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R, 60 minutes (Box 40, Disc 2)
    - Episode: Teacher's Intro
      - Recording, 1 video U-matic (Box 40, Tape 3)
      - Recording, 1 video VHS (Box 40, Video 3)
      - Recording, 1 disc DVD-R (Box 40, Disk 3)
  - Audio Cassette Recordings, 1969-1988; 3.
    - The Cat Who Went To Heaven by Elizabeth Coatsworth, 1969; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 1)
    - Stith Thompson, Columbus, IN, Folklore, 1974; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 2)
    - Stith Thompson, Columbus, IN, Folklore, 1974; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 3)
    - Children's Book Festival, Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, The American Scene, Friday 10/27/1972. Side 1. Anthony A. Martin, Side 2. Miss Laura Cathon, 3. Miss Isabel Wilner, 4. Mrs. Susan C. Hirschman, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 4)
    - Children's Book Festival, Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, The American Scene, 1972; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 5)
    - Barbara Bates, Children's Book Editor,Westminster Press.Writing for Young People in an Audio Visual Age, 1977; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 6)
    - Margaret Hodges, 19th Century Writers of Fantasy for LIS 224, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 7)
    - 4th Colloquium SLIS Authors, Margaret Hodges and Dr. Krzys, 1981; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 8)
    - Elizabeth Keith Botset, Carnegie Library School 1926, Interviewed by Margaret Hodges, the Village at St. Barnabas, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 9)
    - Laura E. Cathon Interviewed by Margaret Hodges on the Pittsburgh Career of Elva Sophronia Smith, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 10)
    - Side A: Sidney Sherwood Interviewed by Margaret Hodges, Broadmead, Cockeysville, MDSide B: Hodges Family Dinner at 50th Anniversary of Fletcher and Peggy Hodges, the Tabard Inn, Washington D.C., 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 11)
    - Laura E. Cathon on Library Service to Children in Pittsburgh, 1985; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 12)
    - Interview With Gertrude Hays, Arsusberg, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 13)
    - Side A: Student Eugene Field; R.L. Stevenson Side B: R.L. Stevenson Continued, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 14)
    - Side A: B.B. McDermott and Gerald McDermott telling stories Side B: Joseph Campbell, First Page of Finnegan's Wake and discussing The Black Horse, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 15)
    - Hodges Poems, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 16)
    - Monongahela Sal, Swing Away Pearly Gates, Read Your Gideon Bible, Sinner You Won't Find a Parking Place, sung by Robert W. Schmertz and Family, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 17)
    - Reconstructed Tape of Mythic Image, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 18)
    - Side A: Commentary on the Soundtrack of the 16 mm Film Where the Wild Things Are Side B: The Purple Max, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 19)
    - Walter Oakeshott, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 20)
    - The Picture Book 1859-1969 by Margaret Hodges, 1 cassette_tape (Box 41, Cassette 21)
    - Lady Queen Anne, 1969; 5 cassette_tapes (Box 41, Cassette 22-26)
  - 35mm Slides, 4.
    35mm slides that were retained by Hodges for teaching and research and reflect their original organization.
    - Research
      - Celtic Folklore, Archeological Sites, and Art Objects, Including Handwritten Lists of Slides (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Celtic Country and Celtic Myths, Duplicates (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Hans Christian Andersen Research (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - King Arthur Research With Sir Thomas Malory, Including Handwritten Lists of Slides (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Lafcadio Hearn (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Malaysian Library Slides, From Kibat, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Plymouth (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Pre-Colombian Art in Mexico, Includes Booklet (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Research for The Avenger, Including Handwritten Lists of Slides (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Classes and Conferences
      - Children's Book Illustration With Typed Slide List (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Children's Book Illustrators, 20th Century (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - History of Children's Literature (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - History of Children's Literature Filmstrip (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - M. Kimmel's Storytelling Class With Ashley Bryant (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - The Picture Book, 1859-1969, Original Selection, Originals (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - Sixth International Folklore Congress, Helsinki, Finland (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Pictures from Books
      - Arthur Rackham Illustrates The Nibelugen Ring (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Books by Hodges (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Treasure Island and Alice in Wonderland With Typed Slide List (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - The Ugly Duckling (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Elizabeth Nesbitt Room